Matthew Watkeys

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Details

Rhoose, United Kingdom 07468417558 mattrab123@gmail.com

https://mattrab123.github.io/portfolio

Skills

C#

.NET

ASP.NET

Azure

Web API

Entity Framework

SQL

Jenkins

Java

Spring

Gradle

JavaScript

jQuery

React

HTML

CSS

Microservices

Docker

Linux

Git

GitLab CI

Agile

Profile

Skilled and motivated software engineer with more than 7 years professional experience with the full software development life cycle.

A wide experience in multiple full stack environments including Java/Spring and .NET, using these technologies to deliver multiple enterprise level high volume systems. Committed to delivering great quality software and constantly learning new tools and technologies.

Employment History

Graduate Project Manager at BT

September 2021 — September 2023

- I undertook the additional responsibility of managing 2 graduates in our team. This
 included; managing their workstack, developing a learning plan with them, assigning EoY
 ratings and setting up work environments including obtaining access and software licences.
- I ensured they had plenty of hands-on experience in the technologies and projects our team was involved in to broaden their learning, such as MySQL, Java, Docker, JS and HTML.
- I held regular catch-up meetings with graduates to discuss their progress and to keep an
 eye on their mental well-being. I helped them prepare for their interviews for transitioning
 from graduate to fully-fledged employees including conducting mock interviews.

Software Engineer at BT

September 2016 — Present

- Led the design and development of a set of common microservice components and user
 portals based on Docker and written in Java with Spring Boot so managers can review and
 validate the access of their direct reports. This enables the business to manage the
 entitlements that each employee has, to ensure that they only have access to systems they
 need, thus improving security. Using Jenkins as a CI tool to automate build and testing for
 multiple developers on the project.
- Worked on the development of a set of common microservice components based on Docker and written in Java with Spring Boot to unify and simplify asset management within the organisation. This brought together what was previously a series of disparate systems and built them on a common technology increasing efficiency and money saving measures.
- Helped develop and maintain a collection of robot interfaces used by one of BT's internal password change systems. Written using Java with Spring Boot and Docker, this system interfaced with a 3270 terminal emulator in order to reset and reenable accounts.
- Maintained a legacy ASP.NET system to deal with the packaging and updating of software used internally within BT.
- Worked on a confidential project using Postgres SQL to create complex queries for accessing information from various database tables for data analysis.

Education

Computer Science MSc, University of Birmingham

2015 — 201

The Masters course focused not only upon coding skills, but the skills required to become a well-rounded programmer with modules in agile development, network programming, databases, mathematics and more as well as core software engineering principles.

Archaeology BA Hons, University of Chester

2010 — 2013

The undergraduate course focused on not just researching and evaluating different sources of evidence and drawing conclusions but also on different archaeological practices to collect, analyse and interpret data, including the use of software such as ArcGIS.